# **Kevin Joe Ronin**

kevinjoeronin14@gmail.com / (437) 679 2905 / Cambrian Residence, Sudbury, Ontario

## **Summary**

I am an International Student pursuing Ontario Graduate Certificate in Business Analytics from Cambrian College.

As I have completed my bachelor's in computer science engineering I have experience working as an intern in Smartbridge and on MLIT Sol. with a profile as an IoT Intern.

Also as a Software Engineer Intern in Worksbot Pvt. ltd

I am passionate about Data, Analytics, the Internet of Things, Python, Excel, R, Cloud Computing, and C++, and constantly trying to improve those skills and contribute to the community.

## **Experience**

# Software Engineer Intern

Worksbot Applications Private Limited • Chennai, Tamil Nadu 01/2021 - 03/2021

Worked as an intern and created a website for the client having hands-on HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python

## **IoT Club Coordinator**

Karunya University • Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu 01/2020 - 03/2021

Helped students learn the ins and outs of IoT development and also provided support when finishing tasks.

Students worked on tasks that contributed work to Community as well as the College include: Anti-Ragging System, Auto Server Cooling Fan etc..

## IoT Intern

MLIT Solutions • Hyderabad, Telangana 06/2019 - 07/2019

Resolved the Problem Statement for MLIT Solutions in Hyderbad on Smart Illumination System for Poultry Farm and worked on different modules and sensors to set up Smart Poultry Farm

## IoT Intern

The Smartbridge • Hyderabad, Telangana 05/2019 - 06/2019 Worked with Arduino Uno, Mega, Raspberry Pi 3, and B+

Coding and calibrating sensors, connecting them with the modules, and Programming the modules.

Creating Dashboards using Node-red, using IBM Cloud and Watson to create a connected environment

#### **Skills**

Team Player, Leadership, Communication skills, Time management, Leadership, Computer literacy, Python, Cloud Computing, AWS, IoT (Internet of Things)

#### **Education**

# **Computer Science Engineering**

Karunya Institute Of Technology (Deemed University) • Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu 08/2021

Completed the Bachelors in First Class with a CGPA of 7.59

## **Business Analytics**

Cambrian College • Sudbury, Ontario 02/2023

Completed My First Semester in Business Analytics and understood the tool and concepts for Analysing Data, retrieving information, and representing the data using R, Python and Excel

#### **Certificates**

Industrial IoT on Google Cloud Platform, Programming with Cloud IoT Platforms, Google Cloud Platform (Complete Module)

#### **Awards**

"Top Performer" during the Internship in Smartbridge (IBM), Second On MLH Local Hack Day 2k18

#### Social

<u>Linkedin</u>: - https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-joe-ronin/

Github: - https://github.com/kevinjoeronin14